# **RUSIRU THUSHARA**

thusharakart@gmail.com 372/1, Opalla, Govinna, Horana, Sri Lanka 🕻 +94 71 302 2214

# rusiru.me

in linkedin/rusiru-thushara 📮 github/thusharakart

hackerrank/thusharakart

# **PROFILE**

A 3rd-year computer engineering undergraduate with five national-level hackathon wins since 2019 and over two years of experience in software development. A quick learner with a strong interest in algorithmic programming, artificial intelligence and a passion for finding simple, innovative solutions to complex programming problems. Seeking an opportunity in a challenging environment for an internship to contribute towards the organization and team growth.

## **EDUCATION**

# University of Peradeniya, Sri Lanka

Nov. 2017 - Present

Undergraduate in B.Sc. Engineering(Hons.) Computer Engineering CGPA: 3.80/4.00

SPARK X Professional Development Program | Spark Academy, Sri Lanka

Mar 2021 - Sep 2021

A 6-month industry readiness program for software engineers that includes technical modules like developing and delivering real-world applications, problem solving, and soft skills. Earned a full scholarship during the selection process.

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

# Software Team Lead | SternX Engineering (Pvt) Limited

March 2021 - Present

Team leader of an eight-member software developer team who follows Scrum methodologies to deliver web and mobile applications for clients.

### Instructor and Teaching Assistant | University of Peradeniya

2020 - Present

CO321: Embedded Systems for 3rd year Computer Engineering undergraduates

CO253: Programming and Networking for Electrical and Electronic Engineering undergraduates

GP106 : Computing for all first year undergraduates

#### TECHNICAL STRENGTHS

Languages	Python, Java, C/C++, JavaScript	Backend	Spring Boot, Nodejs, Expressjs, Django
Mobile Development	Native Android, Flutter	Frontend	Reactjs, Bootstrap, HTML/CSS
Databases	MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB	Modeling	TensorFlow, Scikit-Learn, NumPy, Pandas

HONORS & AWARDS	
1st Runner up of MoraXtreme 6.0 (of 180+ teams)	Oct. 2021
12 hour competitive programming competition for university undergraduates in Sri Lanka.	
1st Runner up of Douthan 1.0 (of 80+ teams)	Feb. 2021
12 hour competitive programming competition for university undergraduates in Sri Lanka.	
1st, 2nd, 1st Country Rank in Hack the Interview IV,V,VI (Asia Pacific)	2020
Placed 1st, 2nd, 1st country rank and 88/4353, 343/3077, 195/2530 respectively in Asia Pacific region	n
2nd Runner up of HackDown 2020 (of 200+ teams)   Competitive programming competition	Apr. 2020
208th world rank of IEEEXtreme 15.0 (of 5500+ global teams)	Oct. 2021
24 hour competitive programming competition for university undergraduates worldwide.	
2nd Runner up of hackStat 2.0 (of 90+ teams)	Oct. 2019
Competition in data analysis and prediction on an insurance data set.	
2nd Runner up of UoJCoders v1.0 (of 100+ teams)	March 2019
Competitive programming competition for university undergraduates in Sri Lanka.	
1680th global rank of Facebook Hacker Cup 2020 (of 32500+ global participants)	July 2020
Top 20 country rank of Google Code Jam, Hash Code, Kick Start	2019 - 2020
Gold Medal in Sri Lankan Physics Olympiad   National Rank - 2nd, Score : 96/100	2016

An annual competition held among high school students to select delegations for the APhO and IPhO.

# **PROJECTS**

1 10 12 0 13	
Identity Access Management (IAM) System for University of Peradeniya  Defining and managing the roles and access privileges of individual network entities of the UoP.  Technologies: Express.js, React.js, Web Security, Authentication, Authorization	Ongoir
National Covid 19 Management System Full-stack web application showcasing country level, district level, hospital level, and overall patie statistics of daily Covid-19 updates and the patient management system. Technologies: Java, Spring Boot, Spring Data JPA, Hibernate, Spring Security, React, PostgreSQL	202 nt
Swarm Robots Platform  Obstacle bots that are localized with an overhead camera setup with the capability of position themselves without collisions forming challenging patterns.  Technologies: Django, OpenCV, Numpy, Three.js, CSS, HTML, MQTT, GRPC  Techniques: Stochastic gradient descent, PID, Image processing, Encryption	202 ing
Project MESOW A portable device for the visually impaired, which is getting a video stream of the surrounding, analyse tand sends a real-time acknowledgment of the surrounding via voice.  Technologies: Python, OpenCV, Numpy, AI, NLP	Ongoir ses
Airport Ticket Booking System Web application and Mobile Application with a Database Management System for passengers and airp Technologies: Dart, MySQL, PHP, HTML, CSS	202 orts.
Crossword Puzzle Game  An instant game developed for Facebook focusing children where they can select and solve a crosswo Technologies: React.js	202 rd puzzle.
Auction Server Implemented a sample server that can be used by clients to bid for items in a stock exchange. Technologies: Java   Techniques: Threads, Synchronization primitives, Sockets, OOP, and Collections CERTIFICATES AND COURSES	201
Introduction to Cybersecurity   Cisco Networking Academy	Jan. 202
Data Structures and Algorithms Specialization   UC San Diego   Coursera Deep Learning Specialization   deeplearning.ai   Coursera	202 202
Al for Medicine Specialization   deeplearning.ai   Coursera	202
AWS Computer Vision: Getting started with GluonCV   AWS   Coursera	202
Cisco Certified Network Associate Routing and Switching	2019 - 202
Routing and Switching Essentials, Introduction to Networks   Cisco Networking Academy  Fundamentals of Business Economics   Chartered Institute of Management Accountants (CIMA)	May 201
EXTRA CURRICULAR	
Feaching Data Structures and algorithms with Hackers' Club for all undergraduates at UoP	202
Creating coding problems for five <u>HackerRank programming competitions</u> of UoP	202
Volunteer teaching   Maths, Science and English at Omaththa College, Mathugama	2019 - 202
Captain   Main Chess Team, Taxila Central College, Horana, Sri Lanka Have won multiple achievements including 1st runner-up in district level	2008 - 201
Senior House Captain   Taxila Central College, Horana, Sri Lanka  REFERENCE	201

Prof. Suranga Nanayakkara <a href="mailto:suranga@ahlab.org">suranga@ahlab.org</a> Associate Professor, Augmented Human Lab, Auckland Bioengineering Institute, University of Auckland, New Zealand. +64 20 490 6990

Prof. Roshan Ragel roshanr@pdn.ac.lk Professor, Dept. of Computer Engineering, Faculty of Engineering, University of Peradeniya, Sri Lanka. +94 77 385 7755